<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Using SSL on Pgjdbc</title><link>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/</link><description>Recent content in Using SSL on Pgjdbc</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 22:46:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Using SSL</title><link>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/ssl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 22:46:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/ssl/</guid><description>Configuring the Server Configuring the PostgreSQL™ server for SSL is covered in the main documentation, so it will not be repeated here. There are also instructions in the source certdir Before trying to access your SSL enabled server from Java, make sure you can get to it via psql. You should see output like the following if you have established a SSL connection.
$ ./bin/psql -h localhost -U postgres psql (9.</description></item><item><title>Custom SSLSocketFactory</title><link>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/ssl-factory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 22:46:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/ssl-factory/</guid><description>PostgreSQL™ provides a way for developers to customize how a SSL connection is established. This may be used to provide a custom certificate source or other extensions by allowing the developer to create their own SSLContext instance. The connection URL parameters sslfactory allow the user to specify which custom class to use for creating the SSLSocketFactory. The class name specified by sslfactory must extend javax.net.ssl.SSLSocketFactory and be available to the driver&amp;rsquo;s classloader.</description></item><item><title>Configuring the Client</title><link>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/ssl-client/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 22:46:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>http://localhost:1313/documentation/chapter4/ssl-client/</guid><description>There are a number of connection parameters for configuring the client for SSL. See SSL Connection parameters
The simplest being ssl=true, passing this into the driver will cause the driver to validate both the SSL certificate and verify the hostname (same as verify-full). Note this is different than libpq which defaults to a non-validating SSL connection.
In this mode, when establishing a SSL connection the JDBC driver will validate the server&amp;rsquo;s identity preventing &amp;ldquo;man in the middle&amp;rdquo; attacks.</description></item></channel></rss>